<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<asset name="Alfzar">
 <pos>
  <x>4005.825609</x>
  <y>-3420.358790</y>
 </pos>
 <GFX>
  <space>M00.png</space>
  <exterior>forest2.png</exterior>
 </GFX>
 <presence>
  <faction>Sartaza of Betelgeuse</faction>
  <value>500.000000</value>
  <range>3</range>
 </presence>
 <general>
  <class>A</class>
  <population>0</population>
  <hide>0.250000</hide>
  <services>
   <land/>
   <refuel/>
   <bar/>
   <missions/>
  </services>
  <description>"Usually the giant stars have many planets, and Betelgeuse, with forty-seven, is no exception. Of these, six have intelligent native races, and the combined resources of the whole system are considerable, even in a civilization used to thinking in terms of thousands of stars.
  When the first Terrestrial explorers arrived, almost a thousand years previously, they found that the people of Alfzar had already mastered interplanetary travel and were in the process of conquering the other worlds -- a process speeded up by their rapid adoption of the more advanced human technology.
  
However, they had not attempted to establish an empire on the scale of Sol or Merseia, contenting themselves with maintaining hegemony over enough neighbor suns to protect their home. There had been clashes with the expanding powers around them, but generations of wily Sartazes had found it profitable to play their potential enemies off against each other; and the great states had, in turn, found it expedient to maintain Betelgeuse as a buffer against their rivals and against the peripheral barbarians." ("Honourable Enemies")
  
But the gathering tension between Terra and Merseia had raised Betelgeuse to a position of critical importance. Lying squarely between the two great empires, she was in a position with her powerful fleet to command the most direct route between them and, if allied with either one, to strike at the heart of the other. If Merseia could get the alliance, it would very probably be the last preparation she considered necessary for war with Terra. If Terra could get it, Merseia would suddenly be in a deteriorated position and would almost have to make concessions. 
</description>
<bar>The Sartaz's court is famed for its glorious exuberance, a débauche of luxuries to rival Terra. This bar caters to Betelgian nobles passing through and reflect it - decorated in multicolor pelts of exotic faunas and pillars of glittering stones, it looks more like the palace of a minor duke.</bar>
    <luadata>{
	humanFertility = 0.8,
	minerals = 1,
	nativeFertility = 1.2,
	settlements = {
		betelgeuseans = {
			agriculture = 1.2,
			industry = 1,
			military = 1,
			population = 7448545968,
			services = 0.8,
			stability = 0.9,
			technology = 0.8,
			activeEffects = { },
			lesserGoodsDemand = { },
			lesserGoodsSupply = { },
			suppressGoodSupply = { },
			extraGoodsDemand = {
				{
							demand = 20,
							price = 3,
							type = "Luxury Goods",
						},
						{
							demand = 20,
							price = 3,
							type = "Gourmet Food",
						},
						{
							demand = 10,
							price = 4,
							type = "Exotic Food",
						},
						{
							demand = 10,
							price = 4,
							type = "Exotic Furs",
						},
			},
			extraGoodsSupply = {
			},
			suppressGoodDemand = {
			},
		},
	},
}</luadata>
  
 </general>
</asset>
