<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<asset name="Ardarshir">
 <pos>
  <x>4041.089733</x>
  <y>-4571.068714</y>
 </pos>
 <GFX>
  <space>M02.png</space>
  <exterior>forest2.png</exterior>
 </GFX>
 <presence>
  <faction>Roidhunate of Ardarshir</faction>
  <value>400.000000</value>
  <range>0</range>
 </presence>
 <general>
  <class>A</class>
  <population>5000000000</population>
  <hide>0.0000</hide>
  <services>
   <land/>
   <refuel/>
   <bar/>
  </services>
  <commodities/>
  <description>Homeworld of the Ardar race, seat of the capitals of the Roidhunate, Ardarshir is in many ways a sister of Terra - a lush world admired for its natural beauty by human visitors, recovered from the period of hyper-industrialization earlier in Ardar history. Six billion ardars now populate its continents, several more in the rest of the system.

That Earth's most important rival come from a planet so similar to Earth struck many as a kind of cosmic joke; but savvier observers realized that it was precisely the similarities between the two worlds and the two races that spawned from them that made the rivalry so fierce: they fought for the same worlds, and with the same conquering instincts. Only the longer human history had dulled Terra's imperialist drive, drive that still shaped Mersian society.

Physically, ardars are somewhat taller and bulkier than humans, and generally considered reptilian-looking with their heavy, crocodile-like tails, lack of ears and mouths that jut forward. They are however warm-blooded mammals, and raise their youngs much like humans.</description>
  <bar>The main bar in Ardaig's spaceport is renowned for its unmatched selection of Ardar alcohols, many of whom rival Terran ones even in human taste.</bar>
      <luadata>{
	humanFertility = 1,
	minerals = 0.5,
	nativeFertility = 1,
	settlements = {
		ardars = {
			agriculture = 1.2,
			industry = 1.5,
			population = 5485425968,
			technology = 1.2,
			services = 1.5,
			military = 1.5,
			stability = 1,
			extraGoodsSupply = { {type="Roidhun Fine Telloch",supply=20,price=0.1} },
			extraGoodsDemand = { {type="Bordeaux Grands Crus",demand=20,price=3},
            {type="Ancient Technology",demand=20,price=1.5} },
			suppressGoodDemand = { {type="Roidhun Fine Telloch"} }
		},
	},
}</luadata>
 </general>
</asset>
