<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<asset name="Dandalo">
 <pos>
  <x>4005.825609</x>
  <y>-3420.358790</y>
 </pos>
 <GFX>
  <space>M00.png</space>
  <exterior>forest2.png</exterior>
 </GFX>
 <presence>
  <faction>Oligarchy of Betelgeuse</faction>
  <value>500.000000</value>
  <range>3</range>
 </presence>
 <general>
  <class>A</class>
  <population>2340000</population>
  <hide>0.250000</hide>
  <services>
   <land/>
   <refuel/>
   <bar/>
   <missions/>
  </services>
  <description>Homeworld of the humanoid species generally referred to as the Betelgians, Dandalo is a large and fertile planet orbiting far from Betelgeuse' red sun. Its natives reached spaceflight (though not interstellar travel) independently and proceeded to extend their sophisticated trading networks to the other inhabited worlds of the system.
  
Dandalo is today at the centre of a large trade-oriented realm, governed as a oligarchic republic firmly in the hands of a handful of proeminent patrician families, all of the Betelgian species. Members of subject species can however become citizen and reach positions of responsability more easily than in the Terran Empire.
  
The Oligarchy is not expansionist or overly militaristic, but the gathering tension between Terra and Ardarshir has raised it to a position of critical importance. Allied to Ardarshir, it could tip the balance enough for the Roidhunate to consider open war; allied to Terra, it would shore up the Empire's flank enough refrain Ardarshir.

In the meantime, the great Trading Families make full use of their neutral position to cement Betelgeuse as a vital trade nexus between Earth and Ardarshir.
</description>
<bar>The Doge of Betelgeuse's position is mostly honorific, but his court is famed for its glorious exuberance, a débauche of luxuries to rival Terra. This bar caters to Betelgian nobles passing through and reflects it - decorated in multicolor pelts of exotic faunas and pillars of glittering stones, it looks more like the palace of a minor duke.</bar>
    <luadata>{
	humanFertility = 0.8,
	minerals = 1,
	nativeFertility = 1.2,
	settlements = {
		betelgeuse = {
			agriculture = 1.2,
			industry = 1,
			military = 1,
			population = 7448545968,
			services = 0.8,
			stability = 0.9,
			technology = 0.8,
			activeEffects = { },
			lesserGoodsDemand = { },
			lesserGoodsSupply = { },
			suppressGoodSupply = { },
			extraGoodsDemand = {
				{
							demand = 20,
							price = 3,
							type = "Luxury Goods",
						},
						{
							demand = 20,
							price = 3,
							type = "Gourmet Food",
						},
						{
							demand = 10,
							price = 4,
							type = "Exotic Food",
						},
						{
							demand = 10,
							price = 4,
							type = "Exotic Furs",
						},
			},
			extraGoodsSupply = {
			},
			suppressGoodDemand = {
			},
		},
	},
}</luadata>
  
 </general>
</asset>
