<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<asset name="Freehold">
 <pos>
  <x>10533.332254</x>
  <y>4173.584478</y>
 </pos>
 <GFX>
  <space>M07.png</space>
  <exterior>forest.png</exterior>
 </GFX>
 <presence>
  <faction>Empire of Terra</faction>
  <value>50.000000</value>
  <range>0</range>
 </presence>
 <general>
  <class>A</class>
  <population>0</population>
  <hide>0.250000</hide>
  <services>
   <land/>
   <refuel/>
   <bar/>
  </services>
  <commodities/>
  <description>"The globe swelled, ever greater in its changing phases as the Ottokar swung down from parking orbit. Against starry blackness it shone blue, banded with blinding white cloud banks, the continents hardly visible through the deep air. The violet border that may be seen from space on the rim of any terrestroid world was broader and more richly hued than Terra’s. Across the whole orb flickered aurora, invisible on day side but a pale sheet of fire on night side. It would not show from the ground, being too diffuse; Freehold lacked the magnetic field to concentrate solar particles at the poles. Yet here it played lambent before the eye, through the thin upper layers of atmosphere. For the sun of Freehold was twice as luminous as Sol, a late type F. At a distance of 1.25 a.u., its disk was slightly smaller than that which Terra sees, But the illumination was almost a third again as great, more white than yellow; and through a glare filter one could watch flares and prominences leap millions of kilometers into space and shower fierily back." ("Outpost of Empire")

A terrestoid world illuminated by a fierce sun, Freehold is an old though remote colony. Handicapped by its distance from major Terran worlds, it has developed slowly. Five centuries after the first colonists arrived, only nine cities stand on the entire world, and the official population is of only 14.5 million people.</description>
  <bar>This pleasant little bar is nothing impressive, but it serves fine local liqueurs and provides shelter from the harsh sun.</bar>
 </general>
</asset>
