<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<asset name="Llynathawr">
 <pos>
  <x>-10599.579627</x>
  <y>-7552.200484</y>
 </pos>
 <GFX>
  <space>M08.png</space>
  <exterior>oceanic2.png</exterior>
 </GFX>
 <presence>
  <faction>Empire of Terra</faction>
  <value>300.000000</value>
  <range>0</range>
 </presence>
 <general>
  <class>A</class>
  <population>0</population>
  <hide>0.250000</hide>
  <services>
   <land/>
   <refuel/>
   <bar/>
  </services>
  <commodities/>
  <description>"When the Empire purchased Llynathawr from its Cynthian discoverers, the aim had been to strengthen this frontier by attracting settlers. Most of the world was delightful in climate and scenery, rich in natural resources, wide in unclaimed lands. Navy sector headquarters were close enough, on Ifri, and housed enough power to give ample protection. Not all the barbarians were hostile; there existed excellent possibilities of trade with a number of races -- especially those that had not acquired spacecraft -- as well as with Imperial planets.
  
Thus far the theory. Three or four generations showed that practice was something else again. The human species appeared to have lost its outward urge. Few individuals would leave a familiar, not too uncomfortable environment to start over in a place remote from government-guaranteed security and up-to-date entertainment. Those who did usually preferred city to rural life. Nor did many arrive from the older colonies nearby, like Aeneas. Such people had struck their own roots.

Catawrayannis did become a substantial town: two million, if you counted in the floating population. It became the seat of the civil authority. It became a brisk mart, though much of the enterprise was carried on by nonhumans, and a pleasure resort, and a regional listening post. But that was the end of the process. The hinterland, latifundia, mines, factories, soon gave way to forests, mountains, trafficless oceans, empty plains, a wilderness where lights gleamed rare and lonely after dark." ("The Rebel Worlds")</description>
  <bar>The grandly-named "A New Hope" is half-deserted. A small group of Imperial mid-level officials are quietly drinking beer while waiting for their ship in a corner of the room and a few traders sit at the bar.</bar>
 </general>
</asset>
