<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<asset name="Satan">
 <pos>
  <x>9009.642683</x>
  <y>5167.295068</y>
 </pos>
 <GFX>
  <space>Y00.png</space>
  <exterior>aquatic.png</exterior>
 </GFX>
 <presence>
  <faction>Empire of Terra</faction>
  <value>300.000000</value>
  <range>0</range>
 </presence>
 <general>
  <class>A</class>
  <population>0</population>
  <hide>0.250000</hide>
  <services>
   <land/>
   <refuel/>
  </services>
  <commodities/>
  <description>"Centuries before, a rogue planet had passed near Beta Crucis. Sunless worlds are not uncommon, but in astronomical immensity it is rare for one to encounter a star. This globe swung by and receded on a hyperbolic orbit. Approximately Terra-size, it had outgassed vapors in the ardor of its youth. Then, as internal heat radiated away, atmosphere froze. The great blue sun melted the oceans and boiled the air back into fluidity. For some years, appalling violence reigned.

Eventually interstellar cold would have reclaimed its dominion, and the incident would have had no significance. But chance ordained that the passage occur in the old bold days of the Polesotechnic League, and that it be noticed by those who saw an incalculable fortune to be won. Isotope synthesis on the scale demanded by a starfaring civilization had been industry's worst bottleneck. Seas and skies were needed for coolants, continents for dumping of radioactive wastes. Every lifeless body known had been too frigid or too hot or otherwise unsuitable. But here came Satan, warmed to an ideal temperature which the heat of nuclear manufacture could maintain. As soon as the storms and quakes had abated, the planet was swarmed by entrepreneurs.

During the Troubles, ownership, legal status, input and output, every aspect of relationship to the living fraction of the universe, varied as wildly for Satan as for most worlds. For a while it was abandoned. But no one had ever actually dwelt there. No being could survive that poisonous air and murderous radiation background, unless for the briefest of visits with the heaviest of protection. Robots, computers, and automatons were the inhabitants. They continued operating while civilization fragmented, fought, and somewhat reconstructed itself. When at last an Imperial aristocrat sent down a self-piloting freighter, they loaded it from a dragon's hoard." ("The Rebel Worlds")

Though with almost no living population, Satan is without question the most valuable world in this poor sector. Only Mirkheim ranks higher among Terran industrial assets.</description>
 </general>
</asset>
